A Guide to the Gravely Family Papers, 1753-1988
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Gravely Family Papers, 1753-1988
Library of Virginia
34126
55 cubic feet (135 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Estate of Richard P. Gravely, Jr., 1989.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Gravely family resided primarily in Henry County, Virginia. They are early tobacconists and industrialist in the area. Their interest expanded to include furniture manufacturing. The principals in this collection are Henry Clay (1857-1942), Hope Thomas (1861-1947), Benjamin F., Richard P. Gravely, Sr. (1885-1962); C. Y. and Bettie Sheffield, and Mary Ann Reamey Thomas (1834-1911); and Alberta Gravely and William L. Fernald.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1753-1988, of the Gravely family of Henry County, Virginia, including business papers, correspondence, genealogical notes, photographs, legal documents, and transcripts. Major correspondents are Harry C. Gravely, his wife Hope T., their son Richard P. Gravely, Sr., her parents Christopher Y. and Mary Ann Reamey Thomas, and her sister in law Betty Sheffield.
The collection has been arranged into series including: Incoming Personal Correspondence, Personal Files, Genealogical Notes, Subject Files, Legal Documents, Ledgers, Miscellaneous, Transcripts, Business Records, and Photographs.
The incoming personal correspondence is arranged into 7 subseries. Subseries have been designated for Harry C. Gravely, Hope T. Gravely, Richard Gravely, Sr., Betty Sheffield Thomas, Christopher Y. Thomas, Mary Thomas, and miscellaneous. The integrity of the personal files of Richard P. Gravely, Jr. has been maintained. Included in his personal files is substantial information on philatelic matters. There follows an extensive genealogical collection arranged alphabetically by family. Artificially-created subject files follow. These were compiled from unarranged loose items and include some biographical information. Legal documents relating to the Fernald, Gravely, and Thomas families follow. There are typed transcripts of Benjamin F. and Peyton Gravely, and Christopher Y. Thomas correspondence, S. J. Mullins diary, and the ship's log of the "Omega."
A large collection of early business records is included in the collection. Family and individual business accounts, letters and receipts is the first part of this section. A section of private business papers for numerous individuals, arranged alphabetically, follows. B. F. Gravely, B. F. Gravely and Co., and B. F. Gravely and Sons business correspondence comprises the bulk of the company business records. Original order was maintained and there is private correspondence of B. F. Gravely mixed in this material. Additional business records for Peyton and Willis Gravely, Peyton Gravely, D. H. Spencer and Sons, Inc., as well as smaller concerns completes the business records section. Business ephemera consist substantially of catalogues, circulars, and flyers and alphabetically arranged covers. Included are records relating to the slaves of the Gravely family, including Bible records (see Acc. 39625) and account books.
Photographs and negatives of family members and for Henry and Patrick counties, and Martinsville (Henry County), Virginia people, former slaves of the Gravely family, and scenes complete the collection.
Contents List
- Series I: Incoming personal correspondence
  - Subseries 1: Harry C. Gravely
    - Correspondence, 1875-1879 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1880-1881 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1886-1887 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1888-1889 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1906-1909 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1910-1911 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1916-1919 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1921-1923 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1930-1941 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Politics, 1896-1920 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 2: Hope T. Gravely
    - Correspondence, 1878 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1878-1882 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1883-1884 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1885-1887 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1888 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1889 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1890 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1890 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1890 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1890 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1890 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1890 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1891 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1891 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1891 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1891 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1891 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1892 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1892 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1892 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1892 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1892 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1893 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1893 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1893 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1894 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1894 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1894 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1894 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1894 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1895 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1895 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1895 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1895 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1895 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1897 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1897 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1897 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1897 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1897 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1897 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1897 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1897 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1897 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1898 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1898 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1898 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1898 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1898 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1898 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1898 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1898 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1898 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1898 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1899 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1899 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1899 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1899 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1899 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1899 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1900 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1900 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1900 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1900 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1900 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1900 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1904 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1904 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1904 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1904 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1904 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1907-1910 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1911 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1912 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1913 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1914 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1915 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1915 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1916-1919 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1920-1929 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1930-1943 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 3: Richard P. Gravely, Sr.
    - Correspondence, 1890-1899 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1900 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1901-1902 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1904 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1904 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1908-1910 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1907-1962 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 4: Betty Sheffield Thomas
    - Correspondence, 1864 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1870-1874 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1870-1875 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1875-1879 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1875-1879 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1876-1877 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1878 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1879 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1880 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1880-1884 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1881-1884 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1886-1889 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1887 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1890 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1890-1894 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1891 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1892-1899 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1900-1907 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1900-1904 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1905-1909 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1914-1919 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 5: Christopher Y. Thomas
    - Correspondence, 1840-1859 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1860 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1861 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1862 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1863 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1864 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1865 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 186 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1867 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1868 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1869-1873 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1874 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1875-1879 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1882-1886 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 6: Mary Ann Reamey Thomas
    - Correspondence, 1871-1876 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1881-1888 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1890-1894 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1895-1899 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1900-1904 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1905-1921 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, nd (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 7: Miscellaneous
    - Blakeney, H.S. 1903 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Burch, T.G. 1923 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Buxton, Samuel H. nd (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Clement, C.J. 1896-1902 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Clement, Caroline 1880 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Clement, J.T. 1941 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Clement, Johnston, 1880 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Clement, Sallie, 1882 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Coan, Jennie, 1871 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Coan, M. Adra, 1870 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Cook, Miss, nd (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Dickinson, Pleasant, 1831 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Dixon, Alexander, 1873 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Drewry, P.D. 1923 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Fernald, Benjamin G., 1882-1960 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Fernald, Benjamin G. nd (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Fernald, Berta Gravely, 1877-1883 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Fernald, Berta Gravely, 1883 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Fernald, Berta Gravely, 1884 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Fernald, Berta Gravely, 1882-1905 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Fernald, Berta Gravely, 1917-1928 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Fernald, Berta Gravely, nd (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Fernald, W.L., 1873-1877 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Fernald, W.L., 1878-1880 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Fernald, W.L., 1880-1884 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Fernald, W.L., 1881-1883, letters from William Mahone (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Few, Mary Reamey Thomas, 1890-1959 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Fleet, Mr. 1904 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Gauldin, S.D., 1904 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Gravely, B.F., 1829-1853 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Gravely, B.F., 1861-1864 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Gravely, B.F., nd (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Gravely, Benjamin F., 1888-1894 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Gravely, Benjamin F., 1895-1899 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Gravely, Benjamin F., 1900-1901 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Gravely, Benjamin F., 1902-1907 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Gravely, Benjamin F., 1951-1959 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Gravely, Benjamin F., 1960-1964 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Gravely, Benjamin F., 1967-1969 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Gravely, Benjamin F., nd (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Gravely, Benjamin F., 1948-1956 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Gravely, Harold, 1900-1954 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Gravely, Harry C., Jr., 1921 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Gravely, John C., 1905 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Gravely, John Thomas, 1869-1896 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Gravely, John W., 1846 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Gravely, Julia C., 1874-1898 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Gravely, Landon Bruce, 1902 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Gravely, Matilda, 1860-1892 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Gravely, Nancy Watkins, 1864-1926 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Gravely, Paul, 1895-1899 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Gravely, Paul, 1900-1904 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Gravely, Paul, 1905-1909 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Gravely, Paul, 1910-1914 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Gravely, Paul, 1915-1922 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Gravely, Paul, nd (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Gravely, Peyton, 1825-1839 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Gravely, Peyton, 1826-1847 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Gravely, Peyton, 1840-1849 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Gravely, Peyton, 1850-1865 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Gravely, Richard P., Jr., 1929-1987 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Gravely, Richard P., Jr., 1973-1988 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Gravely, Richard P., Jr., 1981-1988 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Gravely, Richard P., Jr., 1973-1988, from Katherine Earles (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Gravely, Richard P., 1967-1980, C. Y. Thomas Family correspondence (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Gravely, Sarah Hay Mullins, 1910-1927 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Gravely, Sarah Hay Mullins, 1930-1941 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Gravely, Sarah Hay Mullins, nd (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Gravely, W.H., 1927 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Greer, J.C., 1905 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Hairston, Floyd, 1904 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Hamlett, J.T., 1861 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Hill, Judith Parks, nd (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Hobson, R.W., 1878 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Humphreys, Thomas, Dr., 1820 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Jamison, Samuel W., Mrs., 1914 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Jorgensen, Joseph, 1878 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Lee, Hope Gravely, Mrs., 1902-1964 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Leeds, Lelia, 1904 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Marks, Mr., 1877 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Martin, Joseph, 1828 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Martin, William A., 1848 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - McCabe, Susan E., 1853 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - McDaniel, James, 1826 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Minter, W.O., 1904-1905 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Parrott, Faith Thomas, 1877-1928 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Peters, H.W., Dr., 1873 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Randolph, Peyton, 1829 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Reamey, Henry D., 1888 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Reamey, Peter R., 1866 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Shackford, Joseph W., Rev., 1895 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Sheffield, C.M., Mrs., 1874 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Sheffield, Catherine, nd (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Sheffield, Mrs. Catherine Hill, 1875-1904 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Sheffield, Johnnie, 1876 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Sheffield, John W., 1878 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Sheffield, Judie, 1877 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Sheffield, L., 1868 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Sheffield, William, 1871-1883 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Simmons, T.W., Dr., nd (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Smith, Edith R., nd (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Smith, Lucy Bell, 1872 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Smith, Lucy Jane Reamey, 1905 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Spencer, J.D., 1904 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Thomas, C.Y., 1847-1858 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Thomas, C.Y., 1860-1869 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Thomas, C.Y., 1879-1887 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Thomas, Evelyn, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - Thomas, Frank, 1911 (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - Thomas, John Y., 1876-1878 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Thomas, Katharine, 1880-1899 (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - Thomas, Katharine, 1891-1894 (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - Thomas, Katharine, 1901-1905 (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - Thomas, Katharine, 1910-1925 (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - Thomas, Lyne Starling, 1878 (Box 26, Folder 37)
    - Thomas, Lyne Starling, 1880-1889 (Box 26, Folder 38)
    - Thomas, Lyne Starling, 1890 (Box 26, Folder 39)
    - Thomas, Lyne Starling, 1890 (Box 26, Folder 40)
    - Thomas, Lyne Starling, 1891 (Box 26, Folder 41)
    - Thomas, Lyne Starling, 1892 (Box 26, Folder 42)
    - Thomas, Lyne Starling, nd (Box 26, Folder 43)
    - Thomas, Susan Reamey, 1885-1900 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Thomas, W. Archer, 1890 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Townsend, Wilchier, J., 1846 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Tuggle, Henry, 1847-1859 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Tuggle, Henry, 1860-1880 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Tuggle, Henry, 1881-1896 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Tuggle, Walter, 1889-1897 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Tuttle, Elizabeth, 1918 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Tredway, Moses H., 1880 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Watkins, James, 1832 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Williamson, J.A., 1874 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Wood, James, 1877 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Wyatt, 1904 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Young, Isabelle, 1909 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Unidentified, Sheffield family, 1873-1886 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified, 1875-1974 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified, 1875-1974 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified, Letters and lists, 1890 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Unidentified, Postmarks, nd (Box 27, Folder 19)
- Series II: Personal files, Richard P. Gravely, Jr.
  - Airplane crash, July 1964 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Airport news (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Archaeology (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Armenians, Starving (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Artifacts list (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Arts and theatre (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Athletics, 1960-1988 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Aviation, 1960-1987 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Benedict, Inc., Investments (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Biographical sketches (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Blue Ridge Airport Authority (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Boaz Foundation, 1984-1985 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Bonds, Elinor and Joe, 1987-1988 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Business articles (Martinsville) (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Checks (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Chinese newsheets, Tobacco ads (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Coach of Peyton Gravely, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Constitutional Convention 1867-1868, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Cord Enterprises, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Dale Laboratories, 1973-1977 (Box 28, Folder 17)